# Desmond Chikumba Moonga

- Plot 97, Kafue Street, Silverest 
  Gardens, Silverest, Lusaka
  - +260 965 948 921 **\** +260 976 011 819
  - moongachiku@gmail.com
    - Desmond Moonga in

# **Professional Summary**

Innovative IT Support Specialist with experience in selecting and setting up diverse technical equipment. Strong written and oral communication skills resulting in knowledgeable, satisfied customers. Excellent instructional and problem-solving skills reduce concerns related to new technology.

### **Skills**

#### **Hard Skills**

- Expert in MS Office packages (Word, PowerPoint, Access, Excel)
- Data entry, Analysis, Interpretation and Presentation with IBM SPSS Statistics and Microsoft Excel.
- Web Development (PHP, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap)
- Networking (administration, troubleshooting, installation and maintenance of equipment)
- Microsoft windows Server administration and management.
- Database development, implementation and administration/management. (MS Access, SQL Server, Oracle 11g, MySQL, MongoDB)
- IT project management.
- Computer Graphics design with Adobe Master Collection (image, audio and video editing)
- Computer Operating Systems (Windows, Linux and MacOS)

• Computer Hardware and Software Support (installation, troubleshooting, upgrade and maintenance)

### **Soft Skills**

- Innovative and self-driven
- Able to work under pressure to meet deadlines
- Friendly
- High level of Integrity
- Fast learner and open to learning new things
- Very reliable and dedicated to achieving top-class results
- Can work outside working hours
- Can work with no supervision
- Successful at multi-tasking and meeting tight deadlines
- Team player who enjoys working with others.

# **Experience**

JULY, 2020 - CURRENT

## IT Specialist/Consultant / Ahava Consulting Limited

- Created help desk tickets, troubleshot and resolved desktop issues.
- Prepared new computers and mobile devices according to internal policies on standardized software and security deployments.
- Answered questions and provided information to customers about new software or hardware.
- Determined hardware and network system issues using proactive troubleshooting techniques.
- Responded to faults in both LAN and WAN networks to rapidly restore connectivity and prevent unnecessary downtimes.
- Offered new customers training to reduce frustration and improve customer satisfaction.
- Developed and tested new product offerings prior to release to assist development team in bug identification.
- Coordinated with telecommunications providers to discern and address third-party outages and related impacts.
- Collaborated with HR department to design standardized onboarding processes and training assets.

- Loaded software, granted permissions and configured hardware for new employees as part of onboarding process.
- Used ticketing systems to manage and process support actions and requests.
- Provided tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.
- Translated complex technical issues into digestible language for non-technical users.
- Assisted customers in identifying issues and explained solutions to restore service and functionality.
- Collaborated with supervisors to escalate and address customer inquiries or technical issues.
- Provided replacement files to customers missing data, media files, and software components.
- Integrated salesforce CRM and other customer relationship management software into support operations.
- Evaluated and responded to incoming sales leads and requests for technical support assistance.
- Developed and maintained company websites.
- Designed marketing collateral and coordinated marketing campaigns for the company on all platforms.

JULY, 2017 – SEPTEMBER, 2017

## Data Entry / The Catholic Diocese of Ndola, Ndola.

- Compiled data and reviewed information for accuracy prior to input.
- Completed data entry tasks with accuracy and efficiency.
- Managed workflow scheduling, data entry and accuracy verification for large data projects.
- Identified data entry errors and reported to necessary departments.
- Corrected data entry errors to prevent later issues such as duplication or data degradation.
- Organized, sorted and checked input data against original documents.
- Reviewed completed work for compliance with regulations.

JANUARY, 2014 – JUNE, 2014

## Manager / JEWSoft Internet Café, Ndola.

- Accomplished multiple tasks within established timeframes.
- Onboarded new employees with training and new hire documentation.
- Cross-trained existing employees to maximize team agility and performance.
- Maximized performance by monitoring daily activities and mentoring team members.

 Delivered feedback to decision-makers regarding employee performance and training needs.

### **Education**

2015 - 2019

# **Bachelor's Degree / The Zambia Catholic University,**Kalulushi.

Obtained a Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology.

- Member of ZCU Rugby Club
- Awarded Best IT Student in 2016

2011 - 2013

## O Level / Masala Secondary School, Ndola.

Obtained an O Level GCE qualification.

- Awarded best student in IT
- Member of Masala Shotokan Karate Club
- Elected to School Prefect in January, 2013

## Languages

- English Bilingual or Proficient (C2)
- Bemba Proficient
- Nyanja Intermediate

# **Programming Languages**

- C++
- Java
- React JS
- PHP
- C#
- .NET Core
- Laravel
- Kotlin

JavaScript

### **Hobbies**

- Listening to music. Preferably Afro Pop
- Watching Sci-fi TV Shows and Movies
- Swimming
- Traveling
- Reading books. Currently ready Think and Grow Rich by Napoleon Hill

### Reference

### MS. KAELA KAPAPULA

H.O.D, IT Department.

Zambia Catholic University, 1937 Ntundwe Drive.

P.O Box 260410, KALULUSHI.

Kaela.kapapula@gmail.com

Tel: +260 964 207 350

### MR. GRENCIO TEMBO

HR Manger

The Catholic Diocese of Ndola, Ndola.

Tel: +260 979 243 904

#### MR. NKHATYA MBEWE

Managing Director.

**Ahava Consulting Limited** 

Plot 120, corner of Kafue and Silverest Streets, Silverest Gardens, Lusaka.

nkhatyam@ahavazambia.com

Tel: +260 977 721 891